Pratik Bhor

Senior software developer

pratikbhor95@gmail.com

07768390279

Nottingham, United Kingdom

https://www.linkedin.com/in/pratik-bhor/

OBECTIVE

Strong software development background, 2 years of professional experience, including 1 year as a Senior Software Developer, and a Master's degree in computer science from Nottingham Trent University. Possesses a sharp eye for detail, a natural talent for problem-solving with analytical thinking, and a profound comprehension of intricate technical topics. knowledgeable with a variety of programming languages and tools, and dedicated to keeping up with the newest developments in technology, eager to contribute to a dynamic team or company by using expertise and experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

ServiceNet Technologies - Senior Software Developer

Apr – Aug 2022

Pune, Maharashtra, India

- Collaborated with the client to understand the requirements, was included in the initial architecture design of the projects.
- Engaged with product managers to design and architect the project.
- Collaborated with the team handled the responsibilities of getting the project done within the time limit and distribution of tasks among the team.

ServiceNet Technologies - Software Developer

Jul 2021 - Mar 2022

Pune, Maharashtra, India

- Created web application to manage the schemes of the company where the dealer can order products. Also, the admin can manage the schemes. -- **Technology used:** Python/Django, Ajax, Django Templates, MySQL.
- Worked with the footage from CCTV cameras and AWS media services for a CCTV monitoring application development. -- Technology used: Python/Django project, AWS, S3, MySQL, AWS Media Services, boto3.

enexion Energy - Data Analyst

Jan 2020 - Jun 2021

Pune, Maharashtra, India

- Built internal tool using python to develop executables that could be scheduled to automatically analyze the MSCONS/UDP meter data files. -- **Technologies Used:** Python, pywin32.
- Developed a tool that can fetch data from the database and perform customized actions on the data according to the German energy market.
- Visual Reports generation after the Exploratory data analysis. -- Technologies Used: Python, SQL, Pandas, Matplotlib.

FUEL - Intern

Nov 2018 - Feb 2019

Pune, India

- Responsibilities include counselling the students in the high schools with physical interviews on the locations.
- Helping them with their career paths.
- Worked on Exploratory data analysis on the data of more than 1 lakh students in Maharashtra state, helped in finding the needful candidates to get the scholarship from the company's CSR scheme.

PROJECTS

File Management Software Using Java/JavaFX.

Module project

- This is a software which has user management and lets the user to manage the files.
- Various operations carried on the files.
- Got to learn technologies like docker to store the data in distributed architecture to promise the data availability and the data security by encryption.

Android Application to provide e-commerce for customized T-shirts.

Module project

- This app lets you place an order through the android app.
- The user can upload his custom design in image format which is to be printed on the t-shirt.
- Firebase and Firestore is used to store the data at the backend and Android studio as IDE.

Stocks Application to Demonstrate REST API

Module project

- Application allows user to buy and sell the shares. Also include user management for the better track of the shares record.
- This project uses MySQL at the backend, Django rest framework for the REST API, AWS to deploy containers, Docker for containerization, Docker hub to push images of containers. GitHub pages to host the frontend of the project which uses AJAX call to access the REST API.

Autonomous carusing object detection.

Bachelors project

- An autonomous car that incorporate an ultrasonic sensor to detect the distance between the vehicle and other objects in its path.
- This sensor allows detection and avoidance of obstacles. Python is used for writing the algorithm that manages the behavior of the autonomous car.
- The car's behavior is being programmed to respond to different scenarios, such as adjusting speed, changing direction, or stopping altogether. The model developed in the project in consideration as a goods carrier in the assembly line for the factories with the ideal paths designed for the vehicle.

EDUCATION

Nottingham Trent University — MSc., Computer Science.

September 2023 Nottingham, United Kingdom

Savitribai Phule Pune University – B.E., Computer Engineering.

May 2019 Pune, India

SKILLS

- Linux, Python(Django), REST API
- Java, JavaFX
- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL)
- HTML5, CSS, JavaScript (jQuery), AJAX
- AWS (S3, Media Services, EC2), Docker, Git

CERTIFICATIONS

- Python Programming Microsoft
- Data Science Kelly Institute